CHIRAG PITHADIYA

Web & UI UX Designer

Profile

I'm a UX/UI Designer, design thinker, Web designer, experience strategist & human-loving introvert. Skilled in XD, Figma, Bootstrap, Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, and JavaScript. Strong information technology professional. I believe that human-centered design creates meaningful products and services.

Education

BCA - Shastri Swami Shree Dharmajivandasji Institute of Information Technology, Junagadh

2017 - 2019

HSC - Welcome High School, Junagadh

2015 - 2016

SSC - Shree Swaminarayan Gurukul, Junagadh

2013 - 2014

Employment History

Total Experience: 3 years 5 Mouths

Web Designer - Vimirlab Solutions, Ahmedabad

August, 2019 - February, 2020

- Successfully identified, diagnosed, and fixed website problems, including broken links, typographical errors, and formatting issues.
- Helped to achieve a consistent look and visual theme across the website by promoting uniform fonts, formatting, images, and layout.

Web Designer - Cypherox Technologies Pvt. Ltd, Rajkot

March, 2020 - June, 2020

- Website Designing
- Design newsletter
- Convert PSD to HTML, css, boostrap 3,4
- Basic Wordpress and Magento Theme Design (not development)
- Handle tasks and conversations with programmers
- Should be ready to work in fast pace work culture

Web Designer - Webtech Evolution, Ahmedabad

July, 2020 - November, 2020

- Conceptualizing creative ideas with clients.
- Testing and improving the design of the website.
- Establishing design guidelines, standards, and best practices.
- Maintaining the appearance of websites by enforcing content standards.
- Designing visual imagery for websites and ensuring that they are in line with branding for clients

Details

Madh Street, Kacchi Faliyu, Junagadh - 362001

Links

in/chiragpithadiya

Chirag_Pithadiya

©P chigspithadiya.github.io/ Chirag-Pithadiya/

Skills

User Research
Wireframing and Prototyping
Visual Design
Information Architecture:
Usability Testing

Tools

Adobe XD

Accessibility

Figma

Photoshop

illustrator

CoralDraw

Web & UI/UX Designer - Universal Software, Ahmedabad

January, 2021 - March, 2022

- Created wireframes, prototypes, and high-fidelity mockups using design software such Adobe XD.
- Conducted user research to inform design decisions, and incorporated feedback from stakeholders and usability testing to improve the user experience.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including developers and product managers, to ensure designs were technically feasible, aligned with business goals, and implemented accurately.

UI/UX Designer - Buildformula by Vshwan, Ahmedabad

April, 2022 - April, 2023

- Created design specifications and requirements in Figma to ensure designs were implemented accurately and effectively.
- Used Figma's design handoff feature to collaborate with developers and ensure designs were implemented to spec.
- Worked with developers to troubleshoot design-related technical issues and ensure designs were optimized for performance.

Language

Gujarati

Hindi

English

Hobbies

Travelling, Reading, Surfing, Photography

Personal Details

BOD: 02 Nov, 1998

Marital Status: Single